Vadim Axelrod

Lead Software Engineer (Java)

Citizenship: Kazakhstan. Current location: Tbilisi, Georgia (open to relocation)

Contacts

E-mail: <u>vadim@axelrod.co</u>Website: <u>https://axelrod.co</u>

• GitHub: https://github.com/axelrodvl

• LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/axelrodvl

I have 10 years of experience in IT software development, focusing on Enterprise Java Backend: developing, testing, and supporting Backend and Message Oriented Middleware. I have participated in developing high-load business-critical platforms for the top 10 banks and insurance companies in Russia, and for a leading EU agricultural parts retailer.

Side and pet projects:

- Vocabulary-Building Telegram Bot ChatWords (https://github.com/axelrodvl/chatwords-public).
- Humidity, temperature, and CO2 monitor for Raspberry Pi Weather Station (https://github.com/axelrodyl/weather-station).
- Frontend for Apple Search Ads Attribution marketing analytics ASA Tools (https://asa.tools).

Skills

- Management: Scrum, Kanban, SDLC, Interviewing
- Backend: Java, Spring Framework (Core, Boot, WebFlux), Project Reactor, Apache Camel, Apache Karaf, JMS, JPA and Hibernate, OSGi, BPM (Activiti), Selenium, Swagger, XML (XPath, XSLT, WSDL), JSON
- Frontend: JavaScript, TypeScript, React
- Cloud: Kubernetes, AWS, GCP, DigitalOcean
- Platforms: JBoss Fuse, IBM Integration Bus 9, Telegram
- · Messaging: IBM MQ, Kafka
- Persistence: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Oracle
- CI/CD: Jenkins, SonarQube, TeamCity, Bamboo
- Testing tools: JMeter, soapUI
- · Build tools: Maven

Experience

Lead Software Engineer, EPAM Systems (Tbilisi, Georgia) for TVH Parts Holding NV, April 2022 - Present

I've delivered a caching proxy service for Acquia CMS using Java 17, Spring WebFlux, and Redis, achieving an improvement in content delivery speed and segmentation support, and resulting in a reduction in paid API usage.

Head of Project Development, Gazprombank, June 2020 - December 2021

Treasury Banking Platform - As a Team Lead, I've worked on vendor-delivered treasury management service based on Java 11, Spring Boot, and PostgreSQL, organizing in-house development, and deployed the solution in production. Supported the solution during the probation period, achieving consistent treasury department workflow, and facilitating the development and shipping of new functionality.

Lead Software Engineer, Digital Spirit, August 2019 - April 2020

PJSC ROSBANK - Developed message-oriented middleware on Apache ServiceMix platform.

- NBU | National Bank for Foreign Economic Activity of Uzbekistan Teached the course on "IBM App Connect Enterprise development" for the NBU developers.
- JSC ALFA-BANK Developed caching middleware for a core banking system.

Lead Software Engineer, Cinimex, March 2014 - July 2019

- PJSC ROSBANK Acted in developer and QA roles. Developed a corporate integration platform based on IBM
 Integration Bus core libraries and services development, API development. Developed technical specifications
 for the development. Implemented business documents mapping, and continuous integration process. Performed
 customer support, production maintenance, integration, and load testing, and maintenance of development and
 testing infrastructure.
- PJSC ROSBANK As a lead engineer, developed the back end for an online sales platform utilizing Apache ServiceMix and Activiti BPM.
- OJSC Rosgosstrakh As a lead engineer, led development of an integration bus based on Red Hat JBoss Fuse.
 Planned and led core and services development, implementation, and support of testing infrastructure and continuous integration process, communicating with Red Hat. Organized and led customer support during development, and pre-production testing.
- OAO NPF BLAGOSOSTOYANIE As a software engineer, developed integration bus based on Red Hat JBoss Fuse. Services development, customer support, production maintenance, integration with corporate services.

Certificates

IBM

- IBM Certified Solution Developer Integration Bus V9.0
- IBM WebSphere MQ Technical Sales Professional v2

Red Hat

- RED HAT CERTIFIED SPECIALIST IN CAMEL DEVELOPMENT Red Hat JBoss Fuse 6.3
- RED HAT DELIVERY SPECIALIST MIDDLEWARE APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT
- RED HAT SALES ENGINEER SPECIALIST MIDDLEWARE APPLICATION DEVELOPMENT
- RED HAT DELIVERY SPECIALIST MIDDLEWARE INTEGRATION SERVICES
- RED HAT SALES ENGINEER SPECIALIST MIDDLEWARE INTEGRATION SERVICES

Mongo DB

- M001: MongoDB Basics
- M101J: MongoDB for Java Developers

Education

Moscow State University - Computational Mathematics and Cybernetics

September 2013 - January 2014 (not finished)

National Research University Higher School of Economics - Applied Mathematics and Informatics

September 2012 - January 2013 (not finished)

Languages

- English B2+ (CEFR)
- Russian Native